Anthony Castiglione

(708) 878-1803 • anthony.castiglione@gmail.com

Lead Software Engineer

I am an experienced technical leader with a primary focus on craftsmanship and mentorship. Currently primarily focused on Ruby and associated libraries and tools. Through my skills in software design and testing, I aim to produce functional, maintainable software that meets business needs, and I strive to teach others how to do the same. Mentorship is a primary foundation for me in order help others grow their skillsets as well as grow my own.

My ideal next role includes interesting technical problems, opportunities to mentor and teach, and the possibility to give back to the community through open source contributions. Aligning with a highly collaborative team to achieve the needs of the busines is my goal for future endeavors.

Experience

UrbanBound Chicago, IL

Lead Engineer

Mar 2021 - Current

- Primarly focused on upgrading the legacy Rails app from 4.2 to 5.0, completing it with a near-zero error rate related to the upgrade
- Upgraded application infrastructure, updating or replacing versions of many core libraries that were out of date (Pow, Active Admin, Puma, Selenium/Capybara)

Praetorian Security

Austin, TX

Staff Software Developer

Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

- Java development on a highly factored service based application architecture
- Added ability to track and audit client data ingestion across multiple services

Kenna Security (Acquired by Cisco)

Chicago, IL

Lead Software Developer

Feb 2016 - Oct 2020

- Responsible for new feature development on a Ruby/Rails-based SaaS product in the security space in an individual role as well as with a small team
- Instrumental in developing an asynchronous data ingestion pipeline for client data capable of parsing and persisting hundreds of millions of records daily
- Extensively mentored developers at all skill levels on technical and career related matters
- Led a team of 3-5 developers working on new feature development, platform maintenance, and on-call duties
- Interfaced with Operations, Site Reliability, and Product Management teams on cross-team collaboration, primarily focused on project planning and providing direction for Product/Project Management around technical roadmap planning at a company level

Yello (formerly Recsolu)

Chicago, IL

Senior Software Developer

Jun 2015 - Feb 2016

- Responsible for new feature development on a Rails-based SaaS product
- Mentored several junior developers on best practices for coding and testing

DialogTech (formerly Ifbyphone)

Chicago, IL

Senior Software Developer

Oct 2013 - June 2015

- Implemented a Ruby back-end for VOIP based phone call processing based on the Adhearsion framework
- Maintained and developed a redundant cluster of call processing software including servers running Kamailio, Adhearsion, Asterisk, and Lumenvox ASR
- Identified production critical memory leak in a combination of gems and implemented an upgrade plan, improving expected uptime from days to months

Anthony Castiglione

(708) 878-1803 • anthony.castiglione@gmail.com

Backstop Solutions Group, LLC

Chicago, IL

Software Developer & System Operations

Aug 2007 - Oct 2013

- Maintained and developed a web-based client relation management and accounting application written in Java on a JBoss/Hibernate platform
- Assisted production support team with critical system bugs and queries as an on-call technical lead, on a rotating schedule
- Ruby/Rails work includes improving cross-product backend import of large datasets, new feature development, maintenance of legacy code and creation of unit and Cucumber tests via Test-Driven Development including major feature addition, overall platform stability, performance improvements, bug fixes, and new issue triage

Education

DePaul University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Chicago, IL

Jun 2005 to Nov 2007

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Course of Study: Computer Science

Urbana-Champaign, IL

Sep 2003 to Dec 2004

Core Technical Skills

Languages & Tools

Ruby (On Rails), SQL, Vim, Git, Linux, Resque/Sikekiq, Elasticsearch

Limited Experience

Go, Java, Javascript/Typescript, React, Python/Django, Common Lisp, LATEX, Perl, Ansible